SOBAN FARHAN

SOFTWARE & WEB DEVELOPER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Toronto, Canada

PHONE

2899232080

EMAIL

sobanfarhan@gmail.com

LINKS

sobanfarhan.net

<u>Linkedin.com/sobanfarhan</u> <u>Github.com/Soban-Farhan</u>

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

Urdu

PROFILE

I am a passionate Software Developer that enjoys making people's lives easier. I am a recent Computer Programming Analyst graduate from Durham College. As a Developer, I implement software and machine learning-based solutions for clients' businesses, while constantly striving for growth, success, and learning experiences.

EDUCATION

Computer Programmer Analyst Advanced Diploma, Durham College

Oshawa, Ontario

Sep 2017 — Apr 2020

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Developer, Durham College

Oshawa. Ontario

Aug 2019 — Aug 2020

These projects were in collaboration with client companies (no names due to NDA) that were looking to add AI and machine learning to their software suites to help decision making.

- Mentored new first-year research assistants and helped them get started with machine learning concepts.
- Attended weekly SCRUM meetings with the team and client to report progress and get updates.
- Used Python and TensorFlow to create basic neural nets for the prototyping phase of the projects.
- Optimized hyper-parameters for different model architectures to improve the model's performance.
- Deployed various projects under different hosting/serves including BlueHost, Heroku, AWS, GoDaddy, Azure, and Webflow.

Technology Used: Python, Django, C#, RESTful API, Heroku, AWS

Software Developer, Durham College

Oshawa, Ontario

Mar 2019 — Sep 2019

The project involved developing an API that would recommend ocean freight rates. The scope of the project consisted of creating a website using Flask and Machine Learning Models.

- Used Python and a few machine learning libraries (pandas, scikit-learn, etc.) to learn more about conventional ways of educational data mining.
- Created machine learning models by using technologies such as Keras and Random Forrest for recommending monthly ocean freights.
- Utilized Keras to design a 10-layer neural network, with dropout layers and different activation.
- Developed a website using Flask as the API to communicate with the AI model in providing recommendations.

Technology Used: Python, Flask, RESTful API, Heroku, AWS

Jan 2019 — Jul 2019

This project aimed to help promote women entrepreneur's businesses.

- Designed a website where our users could enroll in various courses. The
 courses were to help with our entrepreneur's business and help with their
 future steps.
- Created a SQL Server database from scratch to retrieve information such as user details, in-progress courses, course achievements, and etc.
- · The website was developed using C# ASP.Net Core and Entity Framework.

Technology Used: C#, ASP.Net, Entity Framework, SQL Server, Azure

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C#, Python, C++, Java, JavaScript, jQuery

Databases: SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL, NoSQL, MongoDB

Frameworks: ASP.Net, Django, Bootstrap, Node.js, React

Methodologies: Agile, Waterfall, Scrum, Iterative, Prototype, SDLC

ACADEMIC & PERSONAL PROJECTS

Forecaster

Jun 2020 — Jun 2020

- · A personal web project which offers weather forecast for a given location.
- The website is built using Python, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, Django, and Bootstrap framework.

Link: https://weather-forecast-canada.herokuapp.com/

SuperHero API

Jul 2020 — Jul 2020

- A personal web project which offers comic characters from Marvel, DC, and others with character information, and stats.
- Built using Node.js, React, Bootstrap, and implements an API provided by superheroapi.com.

Link: https://super-hero-api.herokuapp.com/

AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Honor Roll

Durham College

Jan 2018 — Apr 2020

Earned this reward by having a higher than 4.0 out of 5.0 GPA.